colonialfirststate.com.au 2013-12-22

# Privacy policy :: Colonial First State

## Colonial First State Privacy Policy

At Colonial First State the privacy of your personal information is of paramount importance to us. In general terms the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) defines personal information as information or an opinion about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained. It includes your name, age and contact details as well as your health and financial information. The following statement outlines our general information handling practices, and is generally reflected in our offer documents. (Offer documents generally refer to Product Disclosure Statements).

More information is provided in the detailed privacy policy document.

## How is my personal information dealt with?

We form part of the Commonwealth Bank Group of companies (‘Group’).The Group offers a broad range of products and services. We collect personal information so that you can be provided with the products and services you request. We may also share personal information with other Group companies so that the Group can have access to an integrated view of the relationship. The group may also tell you about other products and services that might suit your financial, lifestyle or electronic needs. The law also requires us to collect personal information. 

In the course of doing business we outsource certain tasks to third party suppliers. In these circumstances we may disclose your personal information to third parties including bulk mailing houses, market research and information technology support and email suppliers. From time to time we also seek expert help to improve our systems, products and services. These third parties are bound by confidentiality arrangements when handling your personal information.

The law also requires us to collect and verify personal information about you. We may also collect and verify information about persons who act on your behalf. The collection and verification of information about identity helps us to protect against identity theft, money laundering and other illegal activities. Depending on whether you are an individual or an organisation, the information we collect will vary. During your course of dealings with us, we may also collect and verify further information about you or other persons who act on your behalf. We may be permitted or required to disclose customer information by law eg under Court orders or statutory notices pursuant to taxation or social security laws or under laws relating to sanctions, money laundering or terrorism financing, or as required to comply with our obligations to foreign or domestic regulators.

Your personal information may also be used by us to administer, monitor and evaluate products and services, assist you with any queries and take measures to detect and prevent fraud and other illegal activity, or incorporated into statistical analysis. We may also be allowed or obliged to disclose information by law and to report on prudential or risk management matters to regulators and our related bodies.

If you notify us that you have a personal financial adviser, then details of your investment will be provided to them. This may also include personal health information if you have arranged insurance through your adviser.

If you are a member of FirstChoice Employer Super your personal information and details of your investment in FirstChoice Employer Super will be provided to your employer and the financial adviser for the plan. You can elect not to have your account balance, rollovers or investor selected insurance details disclosed to your employer. If you make this election, your employer will continue to have access to certain personal information such as your contact details and employer selected insurance details. You can also elect not to have any of your personal information or investment details disclosed to the plan adviser.

If you hold our products and services through a Commonwealth Financial Planner or your FirstChoice Employer Super plan is held through a Commonwealth Financial Planner, who is part of the Commonwealth Bank Group, personal information may be used by other Commonwealth Bank Group companies for marketing purposes.

You can contact us if you do not want to receive any marketing information from us. If you do not want to receive marketing information from other companies within the Commonwealth Bank Group, please contact the relevant Group company directly. You may be contacted by telephone for telemarketing purposes unless you ask us not to do so. To stop receiving telemarketing, please call 13 13 36. We may monitor and record telephone calls for any purpose including training, account management and security.

We aim to ensure that the personal information we retain about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. If you provide us with incomplete or inaccurate information, you may be in breach of the law, we may not be able to provide you with the products or services you have requested.

If you have any questions or would like further information on our privacy and information handling practices, please contact us by calling our Service Centre on 13 13 36, or e-mailing us at [contactus@colonialfirststate.com.au](mailto:contactus@colonialfirststate.com.au).
